Dimosthenis Pagkas

Brooklyn, NY 11209

Phone: (347) 944-3311 | Email: dimospagkas@yahoo.gr

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dimosthenis-pagkas-b5301aa7 | Github: https://github.com/djpdim |

Portfolio: https://djpdim.github.io/react-portfolio/

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full Stack Web Developer with a bachelor's degree in Finance and 10+ years professional experience in Finance and Audit combined with Business Administration and 5+ years in Web Development and Database. Naturally curious, an eager life-long learner and open to new challenges. Top 5 strengths are Visionary, Thinker, Adaptive, Learner, Achiever, and Responsibility. Always looking to solve problems and help people with catching up the small details.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Applications: Bootstrap, Github, Heroku, React/Redux, Handlebars.js, Express.js, Inquirer.js, Jest, GraphQL/Apollo

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Travel Easy

Created an application to help travelers maintain their trip plans by creating recommendations for hotels and the weather based on their search criteria.

- Collaborated with a team of 5 to create this custom-coded, engaging, web application using HTML5 and CSS3
- Personally contributed to both the front-end and back-end of this project.
- Developed the code for the Weather search and adjust the style for the final look of the app.
- Displayed the weather information from the fetch API to appear on our page and store the data in local storage using JavaScript
- **GitHub**: https://github.com/djpdim/TravelEasyProject1
- **GitHub Pages:** https://dipdim.github.io/TravelEasyProject1/

Bibli Studios

Created an application to store your favorite movies and books. This application allows users to create an account, login, and logout.

- Collaborated with a team of 4 to create a user-friendly application using MVC paradigm
- Personally contributed to both the front-end and back-end of this project.
- Created API and page routes for models using CRUD and rendering pages with Handlebars.
- Major technologies used were Handlebars, Jest, Express, mySQL, and Passport
- GitHub: https://github.com/dipdim/Bibli-Studios
- **Heroku**: https://bibli-studios.herokuapp.com/

mcTech-Blog

This project is a CMS-style blog where developers can publish their blog posts and comment on other developers post.

- GitHub: https://github.com/djpdim/mctech-tech-blog
- Heroku: https://mctech-tech-blog.herokuapp.com/

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Project Manager. Mega Contracting Group

September 2020 - Present Astoria, NY

Manage IT services and Low Voltages, Manage the development of the database. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Guide the development team for the implementation of the company's modules.
- Design company's modules and manage the development team for their creation Requisition, Sub Portal, Safety, Task, Project Info and Purchasing.
- Implemented CCTV to jobsites and access control.
- Manage the IT department and the aspects of it.

Purchasing Associate Mega Contracting Group

Apr 2019 – Sept 2020

Astoria, NY

Placing material orders for the jobsites. Manage the development of the database. Create analytics reports for executives.

Key Accomplishments:

- All of the forms of communications with the vendors and the site teams.
- Guide the development team for the implementation of the company's modules.
- Gather all the data for the projects to create the financial report for the projects.

Accountant
Mega Contracting Group

Mar 2017 – Apr 2019

Astoria, NY

Manage the subcontractor's requisitions, payments, lien waivers and insurances. Assisting on database development and then focusing more into that. Create analytics reports for executives.

Key Accomplishments:

- Managed over 150 Subcontractors requisitions biweekly.
- Managed all the Subcontractors payments Lien Waivers.
- Assist with the development of the company's module.
- Gather all the data for the projects to create the financial report for the projects.

EDUCATION

Columbia University, Online

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, & ReactJS.

Technological and Educational Institute of Kalamata, Kalamata, Greece

Bachelor of Business Administration in Finance